<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Haunted One</name>
		<description>Haunted One Background</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/van-richtens-guide-ravenloft">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="background-haunted-one.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/eterean/dwarven-sunset-ale/master/builder/blind-bard-bazaar/vampire-realm-guide/background-haunted-one.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Haunted One" type="Background" source="Van Richten’s Guide to Ravenloft" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_HAUNTED_ONE">
		<description>
			<p>You are haunted by something so terrible that you dare not speak of it. You’ve tried to bury it and run away from it, to no avail. Whatever this thing is that haunts you can’t be slain with a sword or banished with a spell. It might come to you as a shadow on the wall, a bloodcurdling nightmare, a memory that refuses to die, or a demonic whisper in the dark. The burden has taken its toll, isolating you from most people and making you question your sanity. You must 􀂦nd a way to overcome it before it destroys you.</p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
				<li> <strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from among Arcana, Investigation, Religion, or Survival</li>
				<li> <strong>Languages:</strong> Choose two, one of which must be Abyssal, Celestial, Deep Speech, Draconic, Infernal, Primordial, Sylvan, or Undercommon</li>
				<li> <strong>Equipment:</strong> A monster hunter’s pack (containing a chest, a crowbar, a hammer, three wooden stakes, a holy symbol, a 􀂧ask of holy water, a set of manacles, a steel mirror, a 􀂧ask of oil, a tinderbox, and 3 torches), one trinket of special significance (choose one or roll on the Horror Trinkets table later in this chapter), a set of common clothes, and 1 sp.</li>
			</ul>            
            <h5>HARROWING EVENT</h5>
            <p indent="class">Prior to becoming an adventurer, your path in life was defined by one dark moment, one fateful decision, or one tragedy. Now you feel a darkness threatening to consume you, and you fear there may be no hope of escape. Choose a harrowing event that haunts you, or roll one on the Harrowing Events table.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
          			<tr><td>d10</td><td>Event</td></tr>
        		</thead>
        		<tr><td>1</td><td>A monster that slaughtered dozens of innocent people spared your life, and you don’t know why.</td></tr>
        		<tr><td>2</td><td>You were born under a dark star. You can feel it watching you, coldly and distantly. Sometimes it beckons you in the dead of night.</td></tr>
        		<tr><td>3</td><td>An apparition that has haunted your family for generations now haunts you. You don’t know what it wants, and it won’t leave you alone.</td></tr>
        		<tr><td>4</td><td>Your family has a history of practicing the dark arts. You dabbled once and felt something horrible clutch at your soul, whereupon you fled in terror.</td></tr>
        		<tr><td>5</td><td>An oni took your sibling one cold, dark night, and you were unable to stop it.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You were cursed with lycanthropy and later cured. You are now haunted by the innocents you slaughtered.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7</td><td>A hag kidnapped and raised you. You escaped, but the hag still has a magical hold over you and 􀂦lls your mind with evil thoughts.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8</td><td>You opened an eldritch tome and saw things unfit for a sane mind. You burned the book, but its words and images are burned into your psyche.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9</td><td>A fiend possessed you as a child. You were locked away but escaped. The fiend is still inside you, but now you try to keep it bottled up.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10</td><td>You did terrible things to avenge the murder of someone you loved. You became a monster, and it haunts your waking dreams.</td></tr>
            </table>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_HAUNTED_ONE_HEART_OF_DARKNESS" />			
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">2 from Arcana / Investigation / Religion / Survival, 2 Languages</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Haunted One)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" number="2" />			
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Haunted One)" supports="Standard||Exotic" number="1" />
            <select type="Language" name="Language (Haunted One)" supports="ID_LANGUAGE_ABYSSAL|ID_LANGUAGE_CELESTIAL|ID_LANGUAGE_DEEP_SPEECH|ID_LANGUAGE_DRACONIC|ID_LANGUAGE_INFERNAL|ID_LANGUAGE_PRIMORDIAL|ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN|ID_LANGUAGE_UNDERCOMMON" number="1" />
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_HAUNTED_ONE_HEART_OF_DARKNESS" />
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List" number="2">
				<item id="1">I had an encounter that I believe gives me a special afinity with a supernatural creature or event.</item>
				<item id="2">A signature piece of clothing or distinct weapon serves as an emblem of who I am.</item>
				<item id="3">I never accept that I’m out of my depth.</item>
				<item id="4">I must know the answer to every secret. No door remains unopened in my presence.</item>
				<item id="5">I let people underestimate me, revealing my full competency only to those close to me.</item>
				<item id="6">I compulsively seek to collect trophies of my travels and victories.</item>
				<item id="7">It doesn’t matter if the whole world’s against me. I’ll always do what I think is right.</item>
				<item id="8">I have morbid interests and a macabre aesthetic.</item>
                <item id="9">I have a personal ritual, mantra, or relaxation method I use to deal with stress.</item>
                <item id="10">Nothing is more important than life, and I never leave anyone in danger.</item>
                <item id="11">I’m quick to jump to extreme solutions. Why risk a lesser option not working?</item>
                <item id="12">I’m easily startled, but I’m not a coward.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
				<item id="1"><strong>Adrenaline.</strong> I’ve experienced such strangeness that now I feel alive only in extreme situations.</item>
				<item id="2"><strong>Balance.</strong> I strive to counter the deeds of someone for whom I feel responsible.</item>
				<item id="3"><strong>Bound.</strong> I’ve wronged someone and must work their will to avoid their curse.</item>
				<item id="4"><strong>Escape.</strong> I believe there is something beyond the world I know, and I need to 􀂦nd it.</item>
				<item id="5"><strong>Legacy.</strong> I must do something great so that I’m remembered, and my time is running out.</item>
				<item id="6"><strong>Misdirection.</strong> I work vigorously to keep others from realizing my 􀂧aws or misdeeds.</item>
				<item id="7"><strong>Obsession.</strong> I’ve lived this way for so long that I can’t imagine another way.</item>
				<item id="8"><strong>Obligation.</strong> I owe it to my people, faith, family, or teacher to continue a vaunted legacy.</item>
                <item id="9"><strong>Promise.</strong> My life is no longer my own. I must fulfill the dream of someone who’s gone.</item>
                <item id="10"><strong>Revelation.</strong> I need to know what lies beyond the mysteries of death, the world, or the Mists.</item>
                <item id="11"><strong>Sanctuary.</strong> I know the forces at work in the world and strive to create islands apart from them.</item>
                <item id="12"><strong>Truth.</strong> I care about the truth above all else, even if it doesn’t benefit anyone.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
				<item id="1">I desperately need to get back to someone or someplace, but I lost them in the Mists.</item>
				<item id="2">Everything I do is in the service of a powerful master, one I must keep a secret from everyone.</item>
				<item id="3">I owe much to my vanished mentor. I seek to continue their work even as I search to 􀂦nd them.</item>
				<item id="4">I’ve seen great darkness, and I’m committed to being a light against it—the light of all lights.</item>
				<item id="5">Someone I love has become a monster, murderer, or other threat. It’s up to me to redeem them.</item>
				<item id="6">The world has been convinced of a terrible lie. It’s up to me to reveal the truth.</item>
				<item id="7">I deeply miss someone and am quick to adopt people who remind me of them.</item>
				<item id="8">A great evil dwells within me. I will 􀂦ght against it and the world’s other evils for as long as I can.</item>
                <item id="9">I’m desperately seeking a cure to an a􀂩iction or a curse, either for someone close to me for myself.</item>
                <item id="10">Spirits are drawn to me. I do all I can to help them find peace.</item>
                <item id="11">I use my cunning mind to solve mysteries and find justice for those who’ve been wronged.</item>
                <item id="12">I lost someone I care about, but I still see them in guilty visions, recurring dreams, or as a spirit.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
				<item id="1">I believe doom follows me and that anyone who gets close to me will face a tragic end.</item>
				<item id="2">I’m convinced something is after me, appearing in mirrors, dreams, and places where no one could.</item>
				<item id="3">I’m especially superstitious and live life seeking to avoid bad luck, wicked spirits, or the Mists.</item>
				<item id="4">I’ve done unspeakable evil and will do anything to prevent others from finding out.</item>
				<item id="5">I am exceptionally credulous and believe any story or legend immediately.</item>
				<item id="6">I’m a skeptic and don’t believe in the power of rituals, religion, superstition, or spirits.</item>
				<item id="7">I know my future is written and that anything I do will lead to a prophesied end.</item>
				<item id="8">I need to find the best in everyone and everything, even when that means denying obvious malice.</item>
                <item id="9">I’ve seen the evil of a type of place—like forests, cities, or graveyards—and resist going there.</item>
                <item id="10">I’m exceptionally cautious, planning laboriously and devising countless contingencies.</item>
                <item id="11">I have a reputation for defeating a great evil, but that’s a lie and the wicked force knows.</item>
                <item id="12">I know the ends always justify the means and am quick to make sacri􀂦ces to attain my goals.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Feature: Heart of Darkness" type="Background Feature" source="Van Richten’s Guide to Ravenloft" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_HAUNTED_ONE_HEART_OF_DARKNESS">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Those who look into your eyes can see that you have faced unimaginable horror and that you are no stranger to darkness. Though they might fear you, commoners will extend you every courtesy and do their utmost to help you. Unless you have shown yourself to be a danger to them, they will even take up arms to 􀂦ght alongside you, should you 􀂦nd yourself facing an enemy alone.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet name="Heart of Darkness" />
	</element>
</elements>